Guide to the Richard Morford Papers TAM.361
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Richard Morford Papers
1918-1986
TAM.361
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
12.5 linear feet in 11 record cartons, 1 oversize flat box, 1 oversize folder, and 1 flat file folder.
Reverend Richard Morford (1903-1986) was a Presbyterian minister and graduate of Union Theological Seminary in New York City. Inspired by the peace and Social Gospel movements, he participated in a variety of progressive causes and was the Executive Director of the National Council of American-Soviet Friendship (NCASF) from 1946 until 1981. The Richard Morford Papers document his professional activities as Presbyterian minister and Executive Director of the NCASF as well as his involvement with progressive and activist organizations and his time at Albion College.
Kahn, Kathy
Morford, Richard, 1903-1986.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Series I: Personal and Ministry Materials; Series II: National Council of American Soviet Friendship. Folders arranged chronologically.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Linda M. Anderson sent a gift of her father Richard Morford's papers in 2006. The accession number associated with this gift is 2006.024.
Separated Materials
Approximately 2 linear feet of books and booklets relating to the Soviet Union were separated to the library.
Historical/Biographical Note
Richard Morford
Reverend Richard Morford (1903-1986) was born in Onaway, Michigan and graduated from Albion College in Albion, Michigan. In the summer after graduating from Albion College in 1925, Morford traveled in Europe under the sponsorship of the youth division of the Fellowship of Reconciliation, the Fellowship of Youth for Peace. During this trip he met with other youth groups to discuss ways to achieve a durable peace. In the fall of that year, Morford started as a teacher and principal of the high school in Romeo, Michigan, which he continued until 1928.
Morford moved to New York City where he prepared for the Presbyterian ministry at Union Theological Seminary and was a student minister at Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church. At the Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church he met Aileen Hutson, whom he married in 1932. In June of 1931 he was ordained as a Presbyterian minister. In 1932 Morford received a Master’s Degree in Philosophy of Education from Teachers College, Columbia University. From 1931 until 1936 Morford served as the Minister of Education in the Presbyterian Church of Morristown, New Jersey. In 1936 he and his family moved to Albany, New York, where he worked as the associate secretary of Protestant Family Welfare and as minister of the House of Friendship. The House of Friendship was a non-denominational mission church and community center with a low-income constituency. Additionally, he helped organize and was the executive secretary of the Federation of Churches in Albany and Vicinity. He was also president of the Albany Consumers’ Cooperative during the period 1938-1942.
In 1942 the Morford family moved back to New York City. From 1942-1945 he was the Executive Secretary of the United Christian Council for Democracy, a national federation of six unofficial social, education, and action organizations in major Protestant denominations. In January 1946 Morford became executive director the National Council for American Soviet Friendship (NCASF), which was founded in November 1943. While Executive Director of the NCASF, Morford remained active with the Presbytery of New York City, serving as Chair of the Ministerial Fellowship committee during 1967-1971 and as Chair of its Committee on Social Concerns and Committee on Session Records starting in 1972. In the 1960s and early 1970s Morford was a member of the Executive Committee of the Methodist Federation for Social Action. In 1980, he became President of Chi Alpha, the oldest clerical club in the country, founded in 1829.
In the 1960s and early 1970s Morford was on the National Advisory Committee of the Citizens’ Committee for Constitutional Liberties. In the mid-1960s Morford was an organizer and member of the Executive Committee of the National Committee to Repeal the McCarran Act. Morford was a founder and board member of the Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative of New York, New Jersey and Pennsylvania starting in 1945 and its successor organization, the Consumer-Farmer Foundation starting in 1971. By the 1980s the organization’s work included rehabilitation housing.
The program of the NCASF emphasized cultural interchange and education as a means of strengthening the bonds of understanding between the American and Soviet people. The Council believed their most important project was to promote cultural exchange at the local level. The NCASF set up special committees that sponsored various conferences, exhibits, and cultural activities. The Council also issued numerous pamphlets and bibliographies about life in the Soviet Union, as well as information on American-Soviet relations.
In November 1945, a few months before Morford started as Executive Director, the Council was served a subpoena to submit its membership and financial records to the House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC). Morford appeared before the committee but refused to turn over the records. NCASF contended it was not engaged in un-American or subversive propaganda activities and was not, therefore, subject Committee’s authority or demand for its private records. After legal proceedings which included an unsuccessful appeal to the Supreme Court, Morford served three months for contempt of Congress in August through November 1950. In 1947, the NCASF was indicted for failure to register with the Subversive Activities Control Board. In 1951, the Supreme Court ruled that the Attorney General acted arbitrarily and illegally by placing the Council on the List of Subversive Organizations. In April, 1953, the Subversive Activities Control Board found the Council to be a Communist front organization. Morford carried the issue to the Circuit Court where in May 1963, a unanimous finding overturning the SACB finding was handed down.
In March 1974, he was awarded the Medal of Friendship of the Peoples by the USSR Supreme Soviet. He retired from the NCASF and was elected Executive Director emeritus in 1981. After retiring he served actively on the Council’s Executive Committee. Morford was awarded the Peacemaking Ministry Award by the Presbytery of New York in January 1981, which recognized his work for international reconciliation. Richard Morford passed away in September 1986.
Kathy Kahn
Kathy Kahn (also known as Skye Kathleen Moody) was a writer whose nonfiction works included Hillbilly Women (1973) and Fruits of Our Labor: Soviet and American Workers Talking About Making a Living (1982). Kahn worked with the Society for Soviet and U.S. Friendship and Richard Morford to carry out the research for Fruits of Our Labor. In the several years leading up to Morford’s death in 1986, Kahn worked with him with the intention of writing a biography. In the course of preparing to write his biography, Kahn produced several interviews with Morford and had custody of an autobiographical manuscript that he produced and many of his files. These materials were then transferred to Linda Anderson, Morford’s daughter. Kahn never produced a published biography of Richard Morford.
Related Archival Materials
Richard Morford's autobiographical manuscript and interviews conducted by Kathy Kahn can be found in the Abbott Simon Papers (TAM 346).
For more information about the National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, see the National Council of American-Soviet Friendship Records (TAM 134).
Scope and Content Note
The Richard Morford Papers document the professional and activist activities of Reverend Richard Morford from the late 1910s through the mid-1980s. These activities are documented through correspondence, publications, worship materials including sermons, administrative files, clippings, conference materials, press releases, official reports, and photographs. The activities most reflected in this collection include his time as a student at Albion College, his work as a minister in Morristown, NJ and Albany, NY, his involvement in peace movements and the Christian left, his involvement with the Presbytery of New York City, and his role as Executive Director of the National Council of American-Soviet Friendship from 1946 until 1981. This collection also includes notes written by Morford in the course of preparing for his biography to be written by Kathy Kahn in the 1980s. Some notes were written by Kahn or are a dialogue between the two; these notes can be found interspersed with earlier material as well as on their own.
Albion College.; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971.; Lamont, Corliss, 1902-1995.; Melish, William Howard, 1910-; Morford, Aileen, 1901-1984; Morford, Richard, 1903-1986.; National Council of American-Soviet Friendship (U.S.).; Union Theological Seminary (New York, N.Y.).; United Christian Council for Democracy.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities.; United States. Subversive Activities Control Board.; Administrative records.; Albany (N.Y.); Antinuclear movement |z New York (State) |z New York.; Antinuclear movement.; Clippings (information artifacts); Consumer cooperatives.; Correspondence.; Memorandums.; Michigan; Morristown (N.J.); Moscow (Russia); New York (N.Y.); Nuclear disarmament.; Pacifists.; Pamphlets.; Peace movements |z New York (State) |z New York.; Peace movements.; Presbyterian Church.; Presbyterians |z United States.; Reproductive rights |z United States.; Sermons.; Soviet Union.; United States |x Foreign relations |z Soviet Union.
- Series I: Personal and Ministry Materials, 1918-1986
  Scope and Content Note
  This series documents Richard Morford’s activities outside of the National Council for American-Soviet Friendship, from high school in Onaway, Michigan to New York City in the 1980s. There are materials from his high school and college education, including his high school project “Seeing America First,” and the Albion College newspaper, college publications, and clippings relating to Albion College President John W. Laird. There are also Albion College alumni materials from the 1980s. Morford’s trip to Europe in the summer of 1925 is documented through memorabilia, notes, and publications. School newspapers, class plays, and photographs of a school trip to Washington, D.C. document his work as a teacher and principal in Romeo, Michigan. This series also documents Morford’s activities as minister of the Presbyterian Church in Morristown and of the House of Friendship in Albany in the 1930s and early 1940s. These materials include information bulletins, programs, programming calendars, Christmas services and programming, youth group materials, materials for worship services, sermons, devotions, photographs of youth activities, and educational materials, including materials for two Sunday school courses taught by Aileen Morford in Morristown. Documents from this time, including administrative materials, also relate to Protestant Family Welfare.
  There are many materials relating to consumer cooperatives in New Jersey, Albany, and New York City from the 1930s through the 1980s. These materials include newsletters, flyers, booklets, budgets, committee reports, correspondence, and research materials on other cooperatives and cooperatives in general. United Christian Council for Democracy materials include a statement of purpose, executive committee materials, program recommendations, bulletins, and official and personal correspondence. There are materials, including administrative documents, correspondence, and speeches, reflecting Morford’s involvement with the national Presbytery, the Presbytery of New York City, and the Chi Alpha clergy study group. This series also contains documents reflecting Morford’s involvement in political organizations and activism, including the Morristown Socialist Party, and research materials on war and world peace. A substantial amount of political and activist materials are from the 1980s, when Morford was involved with the Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights, the antinuclear and peace movements, and gay and lesbian concerns in the Presbytery of New York City. There are materials from the 1982 Religious Workers for Saving the Sacred Gift of Life from Nuclear Catastrophe Moscow Conference, which Morford attended.
  - Madison Avenue Presbyterian Church, 1918, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Seeing America First" Notes and Drafts, circa 1918 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Seeing America First" Volume I (I), circa 1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Seeing America First" Volume I (II), circa 1918 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Seeing America First" Volume II (I), circa 1918 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Seeing America First" Volume II (II), circa 1918 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Seeing America First" Volume III (I), circa 1918 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Seeing America First" Volume III (II), circa 1918 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Onaway High School: Grade 12 Notebook, 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Inauguration of the Sixth President of Albion College, Oct 1921 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Pleiad (Albion College), May 1923-Nov 1923 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - The Albionian, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Albion College Handbook, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Albion College Pleiad, Feb 1924 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Albion College Pleiad, Mar 1924 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Albion College Pleiad, Apr 1924 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Albion College Pleiad, May 1924-Jun 1924 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Albion College Pleiad, Sep 1924-Oct 1924 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Albion College Pleiad, Nov 1924 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Albion College Pleiad, Dec 1924 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Albion College: Clippings, circa 1924 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Albion College: The Maelstrom, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Albion Reunion Homecoming, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Albionian, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Albion College, 1924-1925 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Albion College Pleiad, Jan 1925 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Albion College Pleiad, Feb 1925 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Albion College Pleiad, Mar 1925 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Diary Entry, circa 1925 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Trip to Europe: Germany and Switzerland, circa 1925 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Trip to Europe: United Kingdom (Includes World Federation of Education Associations), circa 1925 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Peace and Anti-War Pamphlets, circa 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Romeo High School, circa 1925-1928, 1981-1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Peace Materials, circa 1925-1935 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Sermons 1-10, Aug 1926-Dec 1929 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Romeo's Juliet, Nov 1927 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Romeo's Juliet, Dec 1927 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Romeo's Juliet, Jan 1928 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Romeo's Juliet, Feb 1928 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Romeo's Juliet, Mar 1928 - Apr 1928 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Romeo's Juliet, May 1928 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Romeo's Juliet, Sep 1927 - Oct 1927 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Romeo High School, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Test Materials: Religious Thinking, Character, International Attitudes, circa 1928-1932 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - World Peace and War: Publications and Clippings, 1928-1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sermons: 11-19, Jun 1929-Dec 1930 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Vacation Bible School, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Morristown, NJ: Sunday School: The Christan Home Course [Taught by Aileen Morford], 1930-1933 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Morristown, NJ: Socialist Party (I), 1930-1935 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Morristown, NJ: Socialist Party (II), 1930-1935 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sermons: 20-29, Jan 1931-Nov 1931 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The World Tomorrow, 1931, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook: Newspaper Clippings Regarding Presbyterian Church, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Text of the Famous "The Gate" Oxenham, circa 1931-1936 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - House of Friendship, American Youth Congress, Committee on Congress of Youth, Albany Church Publications, 1931-1941 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sermons: 30-37, Mar 1932-Aug 1932 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Sermons: 38-42, Nov 1932-Jun 1933 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Protestant Family Welfare, Sermons, 1932-1940 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Sermons: 43-56, Jul 1933-May 1936 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Morristown, NJ: Presbyterian Church Bulletins of Information and Programs, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "The Necessity of Socialism" Placard, Apr 1934 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Morristown, NJ: Presbyterian Church Bulletins of Information, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Morristown, NJ: Sunday School: Great Modern Christians [Taught by Aileen Morford], 1934-1935 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Morristown, NJ: Presbyterian Church Bulletins of Information and Programs, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Morristown, NJ: Consumer Cooperatives, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Sermons: 57-65, Aug 1936-Nov 1936 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Protestant Family Welfare, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Sermons: 75-88, Dec 1936-Mar 1937 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Morristown, NJ: Presbyterian Church Bulletins of Information, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Morristown, NJ: Resignation, Personal Correspondence, and Clippings, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - House of Friendship Programs, circa 1936-1942 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "The Church" Essay, circa 1936-1942, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Albany, NY: Consumer Cooperatives (I), 1936-1943 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Albany, NY: Consumer Cooperatives (II), 1936-1943 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Sermons: 89-103, Apr 1937-Jun 1937 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Sermons: 104-117, Jul 1937-Nov 1937 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - House of Friendshio: Worship Materials, 1937-1941 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - House of Friendship, circa 1937-1942 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - House of Friendship: Letters When Hired Staff, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Sermons: Notes and Drafts, circa 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Protestant Family Welfare and House of Friendship Materials, Personal Correspondence, 1938-1941 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - House of Friendship: Devotions, 1938-1941 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Albany, NY: Housing, Speech Material, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Sermons: Notes and Drafts, circa 1939 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Protestant Family Welfare and House of Friendship, 1939-1941 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Sermons: Notes and Drafts, circa 1939-1941 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - House of Friendship: Worship Matters, circa 1939-1942 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Sermons: Notes and Drafts, circa 1939-1942 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Sermons: Notes and Drafts, circa 1939-1942 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - United Christian Council for Democracy Bibliography, circa 1940-1943 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Harry F. Ward Correspondence, Apr 1941-May 1941 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Church School, circa 1941 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Free Elections, American Peace Mobilization, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - House of Friendship, Health and Welfare Agencies, 1941, circa 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Sermons: Notes and Drafts, circa 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Sermons: Notes and Drafts, circa 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Personal Correspondence and Notes, Church Documents, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - House of Friendship: General, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Malvern Movement, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - United Christian Council for Democracy, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Federation of Churches, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - United Christian Council for Democracy: Statement of Purpose and Comments, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - United Christian Council for Democracy (Includes Notes), 1942, circa 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Presbytery of New York, 1942-1947 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - United Christian Council for Democracy, 1943-1948 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - United Christian Council for Democracy: Publications, Bulletins, Events, 1945-1947 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Albany Consumers' Cooperative, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Mornigside Co-op and Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - People's Institute of Applied Research (Includes Notes), 1947, circa 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Peace and Anti-War Materials, 1950-1957 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Harry Bridges Research File, 1950-1974 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative: Profit Sharing Retirement Trust for Employees, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Civil Liberties and HUAC, 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Presbytery of New York, 1955-1969 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Methodist Federation for Social Action, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Willard Uphaus Research File, 1956-1971 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Peacemaking Sharing Fund, circa 1958-1973 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Harry Bridges: Report of the Officers to the 13th Biennial Convention, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Presbytery of New York City: Standing Rules and Bylaws, 1963-1985 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Pete Seeger Research File, 1964-1974 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - World Peace Council, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Photographs from Event, circa 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Vietnam War: "The Meat Grinder" Cartoon, circa 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Vietnam War: Lawyers Committee on American Policy Toward Vietnam War, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Revolution in Presbyterian Church: a Statement, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Booklet on Mentally Ill Children, Correspondence to Aileen Morford, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Letter to the Editor Regarding Imperialism, Distrbuted by Common Sense Letter, circa 1968-1980 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Clergy and Laity Concerned, 1968-1982 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - WCP Addresses, Apr 1969 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Visit of Soviet Women's Committee, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Presbytery: Planning Department Committee for Review Session Records, 1971-1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Presbyterian Church: Pension, 1973-1981 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - World Peace Council, Stockholm Appeal, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Presbytery of New York City, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Chi Alpha: Papers Presented, circa 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Chi Alpha: Marxist-Christan Dialogue Statement (Working Paper and Final Draft), circa 1978-1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Morristown, NJ (Includes Notes), circa 1978-1986 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Presbytery Task Force: Peacemaking, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chi Alpha, 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Consumer-Farmer Cooperative, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Chi-Alpha Presentations, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Women's Concerns, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Presbyterian Health, Education, and Welfare Association (I), 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Presbyterian Health, Education, and Welfare Association (II), 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Riverside Church: Disarmament, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Witherspoon Society, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Methodist Federation: Lee Ball, 1980-1986 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Advertisement in NY Times: "Should You Be Forced to Bear Your Rapist's Child?, Oct 1981 (Box MSXOS 002, Folder 1)
  - Union Theological Seminary Reunion and Personal Correspondence, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Presbyterian Reunion: Commentary on Plan For, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "Non-Parish Minister" Reports to Presbytery, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Presbytery: Women's Concerns, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Presbytery Women's Concerns: Pamphlet Material, circa 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 22)